Um, may I help you?
あの　何か
Give me the medicine written on this note.
このメモどおりの薬を出せ
I'm afraid we can't give you this one.
あの　これはちょっと…
Psychotropic substances are
available to you only at authorized facilities
向精神作用の薬物はですね
認可された施設で処方箋と生体データを…
and require a prescription along with your biological data—
Y-You don't get it, do you?
分かってないな～
Someone! Someone, help!
だっ誰か！誰か来て！
N-No one's coming to help you.
助けは来ない
Hand over the goddamn medicine!
さっさと薬を出せ
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
'Cause I feel
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:草泥马 知音   校对:西西   时间轴:葛蔓 压制：娜夏
I can always show my everything to you
こちらは公安局刑事課です
If this moment was for me
現在 このエリアは安全のため
立ち入りが制限されています
I try to hear, lend my ear
ご通行中の皆さんは…
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
何を考えてるのかは何となく分かる
I try to hear, lend my ear
狡噛さん…
Voices inside
だが今は目の前の事件に集中しろ
One link to join it all
So it goes again
#14: Sweet Poison
This is the Criminal Investigation
Department, part of the Public Safety Bureau.
Access to this area is currently restricted to ensure safety.
To those who are passing by, please do not stop...
Hey.
Whoa!
I think I know what's going through your head right now.
Kougami...
But for the time being, let's just focus on the case in front of us.
Okay.
はい
What's going on here?
どういう状況だ？これは
Well... the crime itself is pretty straightforward.
どうもこうも…
事件そのものは明快極まりないんだよな
犯人は堂々と玄関から入ってきて係員を殺し
The culprit just waltzed right in through the entrance, killed the staff,
helped himself to whatever substances he wanted,
好き放題に薬物を奪った後で
平然とそこのドアから出ていった
and then calmly strolled out through those doors.
The security camera recorded the whole thing.
一部始終 監視カメラに映ってますよ
Someone! Someone, help!
「誰か　来て！」
What the hell's with that helmet?
何だ？このヘルメット…
「た…　助けは　来ない」
N-No one's coming to help you.
Anyone'd think he looked suspicious.
露骨に怪しいじゃん
Just looking suspicious isn't enough to set off the security.
ただ怪しいというだけで セキュリティーは作動しないわ
From the time he entered the store,
エントランスからずっと
his Psycho-Pass showed a normal value and his Hue was clear.
この男のサイコパスはクリアカラーの正常値なの
This was all logged by the scanner.
スキャナーにもログが残ってる
So he's just like that Makishima guy?
まるっきりあの槙島ってやつと同じじゃないっすか
He can kill while keeping his Psycho-Pass normal.
サイコパスが正常なまんまで人殺しができるなんて
おそらく このヘルメットが鍵だろう
This helmet is probably the key.
サイマティックスキャンを欺く 何らかの機能があったに違いない
It must have had some means of deceiving the cymatic scan.
That Makishima guy who got the jump on Inspector Tsunemori
常守監視官を出し抜いた 槙島という男も
might have used a similar device.
同じような装置を使ったのかもしれない
しかしよ
But is a helmet like that all that's needed to fake one's Psycho-Pass?
こんなヘルメット一つでサイコパスの偽装なんてできるもんなのか
I could understand if all it did was block the cymatic scan.
サイマティックスキャンを遮断するというならまだ分かるわ
But of course, that alone wouldn't get them through security
もちろん その程度のことならセキュリティーは突破できない
because if someone who can't be scanned passes through,
スキャニング不能な人物が通過すれば
an alarm would go off right away.
その時点で警報が鳴るもの
The problem is that the scanner detected the intruder's Psycho-Pass,
問題は　スキャナーが侵入者のサイコパスを検出している点だ
and assessed his Hue as that of
a good citizen who wouldn't hurt a fly.
虫も殺せないほど善良な一般市民としての色相判定をな
Do you think he cracked the system?
クラッキングかな？
That's not possible.
あり得ないわね
The crime took place in a short span of
time and appeared not to be premeditated.
こんなに短時間で 場当たり的な犯行なのに
It'd be impossible for someone to
alter the data without leaving any trace.
何の痕跡も残さず データを改ざんするなんて不可能よ
The current security system
現行のセキュリティーは
is based around the assumption that a cymatic scan is reliable.
サイマティックスキャンの信頼性を前提に設計されてる
That's why, if someone's Psycho-Pass checks out,
だからこそ サイコパスに問題がなければ
問題を起こす可能性すらないものとして 素通りだ
it allows them through on the assumption
that there's no way they could cause trouble.
Even when actual assaults and thefts are committed,
実際の傷害も窃盗も
それを犯罪行為と断定できる機能が
the Drones' AI routines don't have
the ability to identify them as crimes.
ドローンのＡＩには備わっていない
みんな対象のサイコパスだけを判断基準にしているからな
Since everyone gets a Psycho-Pass scan, their judgement is solely based on that.
There are no longer any means left for dealing with crimes like this...
こんな犯罪に対処できる方法は もう
in this town.
この町には残ってない…
Yeah, exactly.
そうなのよ　それでね
So I told him, "That's not my job, right?"
それは私の仕事じゃないんじゃないですか？って言ってやったの
After that, he got this really stupid look on his face!
でさ　そのときのあいつの顔ったら
ホント　バカみたいでさ
Wh-What do you want?
な…何ですか？あなた
I have detected that you are experiencing a great deal of stress.
重篤なストレス反応を検知しました
I recommend you seek immediate
mental care from a specialized medical facility.
速やかに専門の医療機関でメンタルケアを受けることを推奨します
Are you distressed?
お困りですか？
The Ministry of Welfare's Urban
Service helps everyone live a healthy life.
厚生省アーバンサービスは
市民の皆さんの健康な生活をサポートしています
If there's someone who's been
injured or has suddenly become unwell,
ケガ人　急病人の方がいらっしゃいましたら
would you like to request an
ambulance from the nearest emergency hospital?
最寄りの救急病院に救急車を依頼しますか？
If so, be aware you will be charged an uninsured service fee at a later date.
その場合は 保険外の料金として…
これはいい感じにろくでもないな
This is good. Real brutal stuff.
In the olden days, people physically
locked their front doors as a matter of course
昔は　玄関に物理的なロックを掛けるのが当然だった
because doubting others was the basis for maintaining order.
まずは他人を疑うことを前提に
秩序を保っていたからだ
Is that from one of Masaoka's stories about the past?
それ　征陸さんの思い出話ですか？
Yeah. I heard it from that old man.
ああ…あの老いぼれの受け売りさ
We no longer have to operate on the
assumption that other people cannot be trusted.
今は　誰かを疑ったり用心したりする心構えは必要なくなった
You know that those strangers you
see on the street are all safe, good citizens,
道端で会う赤の他人は
because they've all had their Psycho-Passes verified.
全てサイコパスの保障された 安全で善良な人物
This society maintains its order based on that assumption.
その前提で この社会は成り立っている
Just like that helmet-wearing man,
あのヘルメット男のように
if people find out that there's a way to deceive the cymatic scan,
サイマティックスキャンを欺く方法があると知れ渡ったら
パニックは避けられん
there's no way to avoid a panic.
Or if they announce the existence of people like Makishima Shougo...
もしくは　槙島聖護のような存在が発表されても…
What's the matter?
どうした？
An Area Stress Level warning has been issued in Setagaya ward.
世田谷区でエリアストレス警報なんだけど
But more importantly than that,
それはそれとして
ネットにとんでもない動画が上がってるわよ
an almost unbelievable video has been uploaded onto the net.
Look.
見て
What the hell is this?!
何だ？これは
It's begun.
始まった
What is that? What's happening?
これは…
何が起きてる
Makishima's behind this crime.
槙島の犯罪 賭けてもいい
I'd put money on it.
Though...
いや…
What does this world define as "crime" to begin with?
そもそもこの世界における犯罪とは何だ？
Ko... What's on your mind?
コウ…何を考えてる？
This is no ordinary crime.
ただの犯罪じゃない
It's more like...
もっとこう…
something that shakes the very foundation of our society.
何かの土台そのものを揺るがすような…
Whoa! This is crazy...
うわっ　すげえ！
So when they said that they were gonna demo it, they were serious.
デモンストレーションってマジだったんだな
Shall we go?
行くか
So they managed to elevate the Area
Stress Level this much in so little time...
短時間で　これだけエリアストレスが上昇…
Iwakami Yasumi
A Revolution Sabotaged
Before It Began
Iwakami Yasumi
A Revolution Sabotaged
Before It Began
So far, so good.
お疲れさま
This will work.
いけるね
The plan doesn't have to be revised.
計画に修正は必要ない
バカだな
That's silly.
It's just one person killing another. That's all.
人が人を殺してるだけだ
Nothing really serious has happened yet.
大変なことなんて まだ何も起きていない
The really serious stuff is yet to come.
大変なことは　これから起きる
Hey... You're the only one I've told the entire plan to.
計画を全部伝えてるのは君だけなんだ
I'm counting on you.
頼りにしてるよ
This is the Criminal Investigation
Department, part of the Public Safety Bureau.
こちらは　公安局刑事課です
The victim's name was... Fujii Hiroko.
Access to this area is currently restricted to ensure safety.
被害者の名前は
藤井博子
To think that it happened right in the middle of a busy street...
繁華街のど真ん中とはな…
To those who are passing by, please do not stop.
What on Earth has happened to this town?
この町はいったい　どうなっちまったんだ？
薬局襲撃犯と同じ犯人でしょうか
Do you think it's the same perpetrator as the pharmacy attack?
It's very likely.
可能性は高い
Even so, all the people that were here...
それにしても
これだけの人間がいたのに…
What were they, scarecrows?!
カカシか？こいつらは！
The witnesses' testimonies are all very similar.
目撃者の証言は 似たり寄ったりです
They said they couldn't understand what was going on.
「何が起きているのか理解できなかった」と…
I don't think we can blame them.
無理もないと思います
The idea of someone being killed right before their eyes...
目の前で人が殺されるなんて
They couldn't even dream up something
like that. It simply wouldn't occur to them.
想像もつかないし　思い付きもしない
All these people have lived up until
now without ever even considering...
そういう出来事が起こり得る可能性なんて 見当もつかないまま
that something like this could happen.
今日まで暮らしてきた人たちばかりなんです
In the end, no one reported the incident,
結局誰も事件を通報せずに
and the Area Stress Level warning was what revealed the anomaly.
エリアストレス警報で異常が発覚したってんだもんな
And it wasn't just people who overlooked it.
見過ごしたのは 人間だけじゃない
The crime was committed right in front of a Psycho-Pass scanner, of all things.
よりにもよってサイコパススキャナーの目の前で
So the culprit's Hue was also monitored in real time?
じゃあ　犯人の色相変化もリアルタイムでモニターされてたわけか
これです
This is it.
So once again, it remained normal all the way through? Unbelievable.
相変わらず正常値のまんまかよ
恐れ入ったね
女を殴る瞬間でさえたった　これだけしか　変動がない
Even at the instant he strikes her, it shows only a small change.
Again, any possibility that the value itself could be faked?
やっぱ　数値そのものが偽物って　可能性は？
No.
ないわね 偽のサイコパスを捏造するなんて
It's not possible to fabricate a Psycho-Pass reading
unless he's dragging around a supercomputer with him or something.
スパコンでも引きずって歩かないと無理
No...
いや　こいつは妙だ
Something's off about this reading.
Well, that much is obvious.
見てのとおりだろ
No, I mean...
そうじゃない 反応として正常過ぎる
It's too much like an onlooker's reaction.
Look at this.
見てみろ こっちがエリアストレスの変移
Here's the change in the Area Stress Level.
It's going up and down in exactly
the same way as the perpetrator's Hue.
犯人の色相変化とそっくりそのまま推移している
Ah, you're right.
あっ　ホントだ
This means...
こいつ　周囲の目撃者とまったく同じメンタルで行動してたってことになる
that his mental state was exactly the same as the witnesses'.
I wonder if they'll be able to see through the trick right away.
果たして彼らはすぐに仕掛けを見破れるかな
In truth, it is quite a simple one.
種を明かせば簡単なことでね
ただ若干融通の利かないところもありまして
It's also not without its limits.
感度はだいたい３０ｍ圏内ってくらいですか
I think the effective range is about thirty meters.
But as long as there's just one
person with a clear Hue within that range,
しかしまあ
範囲内に１人でもクリアカラーの人間がいれば
it doesn't matter what you're
thinking inside the helmet or what you do.
ヘルメットの中で何を考えてようが 何をやらかそうが
お構いなし
It's probably only a matter of time before the CID notice...
刑事課の連中もそのうちに気付くでしょうよ
that there was another person at the scene with the exact same Hue.
現場に居合わせた人間のスキャンデータを全部照合すれば
That is, if they verify the scan data of everyone who was there.
まるっきり同じ色相の人間が２人いたってね
Inspectors, another emergency situation has arisen.
監視官　また緊急事態
今度は何だ
What is it this time?!
Apparently, an armored car was attacked on the freeway.
高速道路で現金輸送車が襲撃されたって
An armored car?
現金輸送車って…
Shion... They were wearing helmets as well, right?
志恩　そいつらもヘルメット装着者だな？
Well done! You're right. There were three of them.
さすが　そのとおり
数は３人 全員工具類で武装
All armed with shop tools.
This is a separate incident from the earlier one.
さっきの事件とは別口ね
How should we go after them?
どう追い掛けます？
We'll split in two.
班を２つに分ける
Kagari. Kunizuka. Come with me.
縢　六合塚　一緒に来い
Alrighty.
Okay.
はい
You guys keep looking for the perp from the pharmacy attack.
君たちは引き続き薬局襲撃犯を
We'll go after the armored car.
俺たちは現金輸送車を追う
しっかし　武装強盗ね～
So it's an armed robbery, huh?
If this thing doesn't work on them,
こいつが通用しない相手なら
aren't we going in unarmed, Gino?
俺たち丸腰と変わらないんじゃないっすか？ギノさん
Focus on what needs to be done! Let's go!
余計なことは考えるな
行くぞ
But why is the culprit doing things like this in the first place?
それにしても 犯人は何でこんなことを…
Hm?
はあ？
Why? Well, because...
「何で」って　それは…
What's the matter?
どうした？
How stupid of us.
間抜けだったぜ
Since the crimes are so unusual, they look like random attacks,
犯行があまりにも異常で
but what about the victim in the second incident?
何となく通り魔的な犯罪に見えていたが…
They wouldn't have been attacked so
viciously unless the killer had a motive.
２件目の被害者
あれだけ憎しみを込めた手口なら
むしろ動機がなきゃおかしい
What is it now? Can't they tell I'm busy?!
何よもう この忙しいときに
I want you to check something.
調べてほしいことが
I'm already checking all sorts of things right now.
もう色々と調べてる最中なんだけど
Just give me a minute.
ちょっとでいい
I'm asking you because I know you're the best at this.
あんたを情報分析の女神さまと見込んで頼んでる
私おだてられると木にも登るタイプなのよね
Now, now, flattery will get you everywhere.
What is it, then?
で　何
The victim, Fujii Hiroko... Did she get into any trouble in the past?
被害者　藤井博子
彼女の周囲にトラブルはなかったか
Nothing big enough to be recorded, as far as I can tell.
記録に残るほどのものはなかったようね
Did she know anyone who hadn't gone outside for a long time?
彼女の関係者に長い間外出してない人間はいないか
外出していない
Someone who hadn't gone outside?
Someone who probably would've been sent to therapy right away
そいつはたぶん
街頭スキャナーに引っ掛かったら
if he'd been caught by the street scanners.
一発でセラピー送りになりそうな容体だったってのは
I see.
なるほど…
How about this guy?
こいつ　どうかな
伊藤純銘　職場の同僚
Itoh Junmei... one of her colleagues.
He's been out sick for about two weeks,
so he's been ordered to receive health care.
ここ２週間ほど病欠続きで
健康管理指導の通達中
住所は弦巻
He lives in Tsurumaki.
そう遠くないな
It's not that far.
Is he out?
留守か
Bingo.
当たりだな
If this is the state of mind he's been in lately,
近ごろずっとこういう気分だったんなら
no wonder he couldn't go outside his apartment.
そりゃ部屋の外には出られないわけだ
Crime Coefficient is 32.
「犯罪係数　３２」
An Inspector registered at the CID.
「刑事課登録　監視官」
W-We have to go after him!
お…追わないと
Inspector!
監視官　あんたの犯罪係数は
What's your Crime Coefficient?
Huh?!
はあ！？
Crime Coefficient is 32.
「犯罪係数　３２」
An Inspector registered at the CID.
「刑事課登録　監視官」
Warning: Any rebellious conduct by Enforcers will be recorded and reported to headquarters.
「警告　執行官による…」
I get it now.
そういうことか
I figured out the secret to this magic trick!
手品の仕掛けが分かったぜ
Shion!
志恩　この近辺で人がいない区画は
Are there any blocks in this area with no people around?
What is it all of a sudden?!
いきなり何よ？どういうこと？
What's going on?!
The perpetrator can copy the Psycho-Pass of anyone who's near him!
ホシはそばにいる人間のサイコパスをコピーしてる
The helmet itself is performing a cymatic scan on other people.
あのヘルメット自体が他人のサイマティックスキャンをしてるんだ
I see... Then if we can clear people from that scanning range...
そうか　じゃあ　そのスキャン圏内から人払いをすれば…
That helmet will just be a lump of metal. Hurry!
あのヘルメットはガラクタになる
急げ
Let's see...
えっとね ４ブロック先に資材倉庫
There's a storage building four blocks ahead of you.
It's fully automated, so there are no workers.
フルオートメーションだから職員はゼロ
We'll chase him there.
そこに追い込む！近隣のドローンを動員して誘導を
Call out any nearby Drones and lead them there!
ＯＫ
Okay!
You heard the plan, pops!
聞いてのとおりだ　とっつぁん
回り込んで頭を抑えてくれ
Go around and cut him off!
Okay!
おう
And, Inspector!
それと監視官
Keep your distance from Itoh!
あんたは伊藤に近づくな
Otherwise we'll have the same problem as before.
さっきの二の舞になる
O-Okay!
はっ…はい
Attention please.
市民の皆さまへお知らせします
This is the Criminal Investigation Department, part of the Public Safety Bureau. At this time...
こちらは公安局刑事課です
現在緊急手配により交通封鎖を実施中です
This is the Criminal Investigation
Department, part of the Public Safety Bureau.
At this time, the road is closed due to an emergency situation.
案内表示による迂回をしてください
Good! Good! Keep it up!
いいよ　いいよ　その調子
The road is closed due to an emergency situation.
Crime Coefficient is 282.
「犯罪係数　２８２」
An Enforcer registered at the CID.
「刑事課 登録執行官 任意執行対象です」
Dammit!
This target has Enforce At Will status.
The safety will be released.
「セーフティーを解除します」
Thanks for that.
そりゃどうも
282? Hey...
２８２って　お前…
Yeah...
あ～ついぶち殺してやるとか思って…
I couldn't help but think about killing this bastard with my bare hands.
自分のサイコパスを撃たれた感想はどうだ
How do you feel about someone with your Psycho-Pass being shot?
こいつがエリミネーターに変形しなくてよかったよ
I'm just glad it didn't activate the Eliminator.
Looks like you had no trouble shaking off your pursuers.
うまく追跡はまけたようだね
It was a piece of cake.
ちょろいもんさ
ドミネーターの使えねえ 公安なんてへでもねえ
The Bureau's utterly toothless without their precious Dominators.
That said...
でもよ～
Dude.
あんたさ～
You must be out of your mind.
肝心なところで一本ネジが抜けてるよな
Why would you carry something that valuable around all by yourself?
それだけのお宝を１人で持ち歩いて 用心とか考えなかったわけ
Didn't you even think about taking precautions?
This was a tool to promote awareness.
これは啓蒙のための道具だったんだ
人が人らしく生きるために…
To make people realize they should
live like human beings, not docile livestock.
家畜のような惰眠から目を覚ましてやるために…
Huh?
はあ
People have been misled by Sibyl to the point
シビュラに惑わされた人々は
where they no longer recognize
danger, even if it's staring them in the face.
目の前の危機を正しく評価できなくなった
In that sense, you guys are as foolish as those pitiful sheep.
その意味では君たちも あの哀れな羊たちと等しく愚かしい…
Ha! Is that right?!
ヘッ　そうかよ！
ああ…本当に嘆かわしいことだ
Indeed. It really is...
a terrible shame.
There's no way I could love anyone,
Dareka wo aisuru koto nante
Dekiru wake nakutte
But I wish to be loved by someone in turn
The world may not have
Dakedo dareka ni aisaretakute
Ended yesterday after all,
Kawaranai kinou ga zutto tsuzuita to shite mo
But we will not budge
Doko ni mo ike ya shinainda
watashi to kimi
From where we are
Kamisama doko he itte shimatta no nee
God, in favor of which parts have you left us?
Henji wa nakute itsu datte sou da yo
I receive no reply, I never do
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
I walk with you
Anata to iku
Donna tsumi mo
I will share all your sins
Seotte ageru
Together with you
Michi naki michi wo
Aruiteku no
I walk
A trackless path
Anata to futari de
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all individuals and organizations that appear
in this show are fictitious and any similarity to those in existence in the real world is purely coincidental.
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".